this problem requires us to
determine what the given code will print
you can see that on line 7 we
invoke the meal method and pass it to
put s to output its return value
on line two you can see the return
keyword
and the string breakfast on line
three we have the string dinner
and on line four we invoke put s
and pass the string dinner to that
method
so what will this code output you can
see that we have
two calls to put us one on line four and
one on line
seven so you may think that we should
expect two lines of output
however looking more closely at the meal
method definition
you can see that the only line of the
meal method that will be executed
is line two because we use the return
keyword on line two ruby will exit this
method
and never execute lines three and four
so put us on line four will never be
invoked
and we won't output the string dinner we
will only
output the return value of the meal
method
on line 7 which in this case is the
string
breakfast returned from the method on
line 2.
let's run our code and see that
and you can see that we've achieved the
expected output
so it's very important to be aware that
when ruby
executes a return it will immediately
exit that method
and no other code within the method will
be executed